<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Grayson White</title>
    <link>https://graysonwhite.com/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Grayson White</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 Grayson White</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://graysonwhite.com/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FIESTA
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/software/fiesta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/software/fiesta/</guid>
      <description>Overview The R package, FIESTA (Forest Inventory ESTimation and Analysis) is a research estimation tool for analysts that work with sample-based inventory data from the U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) Program. FIESTA can generate FIA’s traditional state-wide estimates while also accommodate: unique population boundaries, different evaluation time periods, customized stratification schemes, non-standard variance equations, integration of multi-scale remotely-sensed data and other auxiliary information, and interaction with other modeling and estimation tools from CRAN’s library of packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gglm
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/software/gglm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/software/gglm/</guid>
      <description>Overview gglm, The Grammar of Graphics for Linear Model Diagnostics, is an R package and official ggplot2 extension that creates beautiful ggplot2 diagnostic plots for linear models that are easy to use and adhere to The Grammar of Graphics. The purpose of this package is to provide a sensible alternative to using the base-R plot() function to produce diagnostic plots for linear models.
Access gglm is available on CRAN and on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
