<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Grayson White</title>
    <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Grayson White</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 Grayson White</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://graysonwhite.com/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FIESTA: A forest inventory estimation and analysis R package
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/ecography-fiesta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/ecography-fiesta/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Ecologists are increasingly relying on national forest inventories to address a wide variety of issues. The ‘FIESTA’ R package (Forest Inventory ESTimation and Analysis) is a tool that enables customized investigations using the extensive sample-based inventory data collected across all lands in the US by the US Dept of Agriculture, Forest Service, Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) Program. To date, the complex nature of the FIA inventory constrains many users to conduct only limited analyses through existing tools with pre-specified geographic boundaries, timeframes, and auxiliary data under a single statistical estimation process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Area Estimates for National Applications: A Database to Dashboard Strategy Using FIESTA
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/frontiers-fiesta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/frontiers-fiesta/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper demonstrates a process for translating a database of forest measurements to interactive dashboards through which users can access statistically defensible estimates and analyses anywhere in the conterminous US. It taps the extensive Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) plot network along with national remotely sensed data layers to produce estimates using widely accepted model-assisted and small area estimation methodologies. It leverages a decade’s worth of statistical and computational research on FIA’s flexible estimation engine, FIESTA, and provides a vehicle through which scientists and analysts can share their own tools and analytical processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Bayesian Small Area Estimation Using Weakly Informative Priors in Ecologically Homogeneous Areas of the Interior Western Forests
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/frontiers-hb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/frontiers-hb/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The U.S. Forest Inventory and Analysis Program (FIA) collects inventory data on and computes estimates for many forest attributes to monitor the status and trends of the nation&amp;rsquo;s forests. Increasingly, FIA needs to produce estimates in small geographic and temporal regions. In this application, we implement area level hierarchical Bayesian (HB) small area estimators of several forest attributes for ecosubsections in the Interior West of the US. We use a remotely-sensed auxiliary variable, percent tree canopy cover, to predict response variables derived from ground-collected data such as basal area, biomass, tree count, and volume.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
