<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Grayson White</title>
    <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Grayson White</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 Grayson White</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://graysonwhite.com/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[preprint]: Small area estimation of forest biomass via a two-stage model for continuous zero-inflated data
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/arxiv-zeroinflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/arxiv-zeroinflation/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The U.S. Forest Inventory &amp;amp; Analysis Program (FIA) collects data on and monitors the trends of forests in the United States. FIA is increasingly interested in monitoring forest attributes such as biomass at fine geographic and temporal scales, resulting in a need for assessment and development of small area estimation techniques applied to forest inventory contexts. We implement a small area estimator and parametric bootstrap estimator that account for zero-inflation in biomass data via a two-stage model-based approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[preprint]: Assessing small area estimates via artificial populations from KBAABB: a kNN-based approximation to ABB
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/arxiv-kbaabb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/arxiv-kbaabb/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Comparing and evaluating small area estimation (SAE) models for a given application is inherently difficult. Typically, we do not have enough data in many areas to check unit-level modeling assumptions or to assess unit-level predictions empirically; and there is no ground truth available for checking area-level estimates. Design-based simulation from artificial populations can help with each of these issues, but only if the artificial populations (a) realistically represent the application at hand and (b) are not built using assumptions that could inherently favor one SAE model over another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An approach to estimating forest biomass while quantifying estimate uncertainty and correcting bias in machine learning maps
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/rse-biomass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/rse-biomass/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Providing forest biomass estimates with desired accuracy and precision for small areas is a key challenge to incorporating forest carbon offsets into commodity trading programs. Enrolled forest carbon projects and verification entities typically rely on probabilistically sampled field data and design-based (DB) estimators to estimate carbon storage and characterize uncertainty. However, this methodology requires a large amount of field data to achieve sufficient precision and collection of these data can be prohibitively expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FIESTA: A forest inventory estimation and analysis R package
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/ecography-fiesta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/ecography-fiesta/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Ecologists are increasingly relying on national forest inventories to address a wide variety of issues. The ‘FIESTA’ R package (Forest Inventory ESTimation and Analysis) is a tool that enables customized investigations using the extensive sample-based inventory data collected across all lands in the US by the US Dept of Agriculture, Forest Service, Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) Program. To date, the complex nature of the FIA inventory constrains many users to conduct only limited analyses through existing tools with pre-specified geographic boundaries, timeframes, and auxiliary data under a single statistical estimation process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Area Estimates for National Applications: A Database to Dashboard Strategy Using FIESTA
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/frontiers-fiesta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/frontiers-fiesta/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper demonstrates a process for translating a database of forest measurements to interactive dashboards through which users can access statistically defensible estimates and analyses anywhere in the conterminous US. It taps the extensive Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) plot network along with national remotely sensed data layers to produce estimates using widely accepted model-assisted and small area estimation methodologies. It leverages a decade’s worth of statistical and computational research on FIA’s flexible estimation engine, FIESTA, and provides a vehicle through which scientists and analysts can share their own tools and analytical processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Bayesian small area estimation using weakly informative priors in ecologically homogeneous areas of the interior western forests
</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/frontiers-hb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.com/publications/frontiers-hb/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The U.S. Forest Inventory and Analysis Program (FIA) collects inventory data on and computes estimates for many forest attributes to monitor the status and trends of the nation&amp;rsquo;s forests. Increasingly, FIA needs to produce estimates in small geographic and temporal regions. In this application, we implement area level hierarchical Bayesian (HB) small area estimators of several forest attributes for ecosubsections in the Interior West of the US. We use a remotely-sensed auxiliary variable, percent tree canopy cover, to predict response variables derived from ground-collected data such as basal area, biomass, tree count, and volume.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
