<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on Grayson White</title>
    <link>https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on Grayson White</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently a senior at Reed College and am writing a year long thesis investigating the benefits of hierarchical Bayesian modeling for small area estimation, in particular with an application to forestry data. I am also applying to graduate programs in statistics this fall, to enter a program in fall 2021. Currently, I am also working as a Course Assistant for Math 141: Introduction to Probability &amp;amp; Statistics, and an independent tutor for Econ 311: Survey of Econometric Methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last summer, I worked as a Data Science for Public Good researcher at Oregon State University. I worked with Dr. Christine Kelly to develop forcasting tools for cost analysis of water and wastewater facilities in Oregon small towns and cities in order to provide city planners with data driven solutions for planning long term development and financial investments. You can see a technical report and dashboard below on my website in the &amp;ldquo;Posts&amp;rdquo; sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have experiance working as a Statistics Tutor at Reed College. While working as a tutor I held weekly study sessions for Math 141: Introduction to Probability and Statistics. I provided students with the help needed to answer questions regarding probability and statistics along with questions regarding programming in R.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Ford</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/robert-ford/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/robert-ford/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
