<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on Grayson White</title>
    <link>https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on Grayson White</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a Data Scientist at the U.S. Forest Service (FIA Contractor) working on the development of the &lt;code&gt;FIESTA&lt;/code&gt; R package, small area estimation research, and many other forestry projects. I recently graduated from Reed College with a Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics with a concentration in Statistics. My senior thesis, titled &lt;em&gt;A Hierarchical Bayesian Approach to Small Area Estimation of Forest Attributes&lt;/em&gt; implemented hierarchical Bayesian small area models to increase forest attribute estimate efficiency using FIA data in the interior west region of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After graduating from Reed in May 2021, I worked with Dr. Kelly McConville at Reed&amp;rsquo;s Forestry Data Science Lab working on a variety of tasks. Briefly, I prepared the results in my senior thesis for publication (manuscript in submission), began development of open-source small area estimation &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; software, and updated &lt;code&gt;shiny&lt;/code&gt; dashboards for the Forestry Data Science Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Reed, I worked as a course assistant for Math 241: Data Science and Math 141: Introduction to Probability &amp;amp; Statistics. I also worked as a 1-on-1 tutor for students taking Math 392: Mathematical Statistics, Math 241: Data Science, Math 141: Introduction to Probability &amp;amp; Statistics, and Economics 311: Survey of Econometric Methods. Also at Reed, I worked as a group tutor holding weekly study sessions for Math 141: Introduction to Probability and Statistics. In that role, I provided students with the help needed to answer questions regarding probability and statistics along with questions regarding programming in &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summer 2020, I worked as a Data Science for Public Good researcher at Oregon State University. I worked with Dr. Christine Kelly to develop forecasting tools for cost analysis of water and wastewater facilities in Oregon small towns and cities in order to provide city planners with data driven solutions for planning long term development and financial investments. You can see a technical report and dashboard below on my website in the &amp;ldquo;Posts&amp;rdquo; sections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Ford</title>
      <link>https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/robert-ford/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://graysonwhite.github.io/authors/robert-ford/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
